stockcharts.com 2018-12-03

# Privacy Statement [Documentation]

**_Last updated: April 2018_**

StockCharts.com, Inc. (“StockCharts.com,” “we,” “us,” “our”) has created this Privacy Statement in order to demonstrate our commitment to the privacy of those that visit and use our website (“Users,” “you,” “your”). We are committed to not sharing your Personal Information (defined below) with advertisers or spammers. The following discloses the information gathering, storage, and dissemination practices of StockCharts.com at [https://www.stockcharts.com](https://www.stockcharts.com/ "https://www.stockcharts.com") (the “Site”), including: 

  * What Personal and non-Personal Information StockCharts.com collects about Users.

  * What Personal and non-Personal Information third parties collect about Users through the Site.

  * What organizations collect this User information.

  * How StockCharts.com uses this User information.

  * With whom StockCharts.com may share this User information.

  * How Users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

  * What choices are available to Users regarding collection, use, and distribution of this information.

  * What type of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under StockCharts.com's control.

By visiting the Site, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Statement. If you have any objections to the Privacy Statement, you should immediately discontinue use of the Site and its services. 

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, please send them to [privacy@stockcharts.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@stockcharts.com "mailto:privacy@stockcharts.com"). 

## What Personal Information StockCharts.com Collects

We collect Personal Information on the Site. “Personal Information” means information that can be used to identify or contact an individual and may include, but is not limited to, your first and last name, your unique user ID, email address, and any other personal profile or account information you choose to submit through our Site. If you choose to subscribe, StockCharts.com or its third-party payment transactions services provider may also collect credit, debit, or other billing account information. You may always choose not to provide Personal Information, but this may prevent you from receiving certain services. 

StockCharts.com, Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on StockCharts.com. 

### Registration and Purchases/Renewals

If you choose to subscribe to our paid services, then we will require several key pieces of Personal Information from you. In order to access the membership areas of the site, a User is required to give contact information, including name and email address. We use this information to ensure account security and uniqueness and to contact the User in case a problem occurs. We may use the User's email address to provide customer support, or to administer and maintain their account. 

In addition, registered Users must provide payment information (such as credit card number and expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes only. 

Note: Credit Card numbers are transmitted directly to our payment processor and never actually enter StockCharts.com's systems. 

### Real-Time Data Subscriptions

If you choose to subscribe to one of our real-time data plans, the exchange you subscribe to requires us to collect certain Personal Information from you and report that information to the exchange. This may include your name, address, occupation, name and address of your employer, and basic job title/position/function information. This information is used to verify whether or not you are a financial professional, as we are not allowed to provide real-time data to financial professionals. 

### Website Notification Features

If you choose to receive optional email notifications from the Site, you must provide your email address. This may include, but is not limited to, subscribing to the ChartWatchers Newsletter, signing up for notifications of new blog articles, or setting up technical alerts. 

If you choose to be notified of technical alerts via SMS, you will be required to provide your mobile phone number. 

This contact info is used to send the requested notifications to the User. 

### Other Email Communication Features

The Site contains links that allow Users to send information (including charts and blog articles) to others via email. StockCharts.com will never use any email addresses entered into our “tell-a-friend” style links for the purposes of sending unsolicited messages. 

Our Public ChartList feature optionally allows Internet Users to contact you via email by filling out a web-based form. Even if you enable this feature, your email address never appears on our Site. Your email address will only be provided to other Internet Users if you respond directly to their messages. 

### Information Sharing Features

If you choose to use our Site's social networking function to share our charts or other Site content to Facebook, Twitter, or any other social networking site, you may be asked to log in to the social networking site. The login information is transmitted directly to the social networking site and never actually enters StockCharts.com's systems. 

StockCharts.com allows Users to share annotated charts and commentary with the rest of the Internet via our Public ChartList feature, blog article comments, message boards, and online forums. Use of these features is considered to be a voluntary disclosure of Personal Information by you. Accordingly, you should exercise discretion with regard to what Personal Information you post on public areas of our Site and you should not post highly confidential or sensitive information. StockCharts.com is not responsible for how third parties who view your Personal Information on these public areas of the Site may use this information (such as to send you unsolicited messages). 

Users also have the ability to add information in other places on the Site, including annotated charts, private ChartLists, and in user-defined indexes. Adding information in these places is completely optional and can be done at the discretion of the User. We recommend that Users do NOT place sensitive information, such as trading account numbers and passwords, anywhere on the Site. Like most online services, we cannot fully guarantee the safety and privacy of such information, whether Personal Information, non-Personal Information, or other types of information. 

### Profile Information

When a User customizes their StockCharts.com account, those customized User settings (default chart settings, favorite lists, etc.) are collected and stored in their profile. StockCharts.com does not use stored User settings for marketing purposes. Profiles are used solely for the purpose of customizing our paying Users' visits. We do not share your profile with other third parties. 

## What Non-Personal Information StockCharts.com Collects

Like most websites, we use web server log files. Records in our log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser types, referring pages, exit pages, platform types, and date/time stamps. We use web server log files to administer the Site, to provide broad traffic information for Site planning purposes, and to ensure that our Terms of Service agreement is being adhered to. IP addresses are not tied to Personal Information in our web server log files. 

## What Non-Personal Information Third Parties Collect

Our advertisers and ad networks may use various activity tracking technologies, such as cookies, pixels, and web beacons, to collect information from any computer or mobile device you use to access the Site about your activities on the Site or interaction with their advertisements, such as the web pages you visit, the links or advertisements you click, or the other actions you conduct while on our Site. 

The ads appearing on the Site are delivered to Users by InvestingChannel, Inc., our web advertising partner. Information about Users' visits to the Site, such as the number of times they have viewed an ad (but not Personal Information like user ID and password) is used to serve ads to Users on this Site, and may be collected and used for the purpose of Interest-Based Advertising. Non-Personal Information collected and transferred to third parties may be used for the purpose of ad targeting and delivery optimization. For more information about InvestingChannel's privacy policy, [click here](https://investingchannel.com/policy "https://investingchannel.com/policy"). 

## Third-Party Links

Please note that the Site may provide links to third party sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies, practices, or the content of websites owned by others that you may link to or that may be linked from the Site. We, therefore, encourage you to review the privacy policies and terms of service of those websites so that you understand how those websites collect, use, and share any Personal Information. 

Several of our partner sites use our charting capabilities. Those sites may contain messages saying “Copyright StockCharts.com” or “Powered By StockCharts.com”. Even if those messages are present, we do not control the privacy practices of those sites. 

## How StockCharts.com Utilizes Your Information

StockCharts.com may use Personal Information to: set up and manage User accounts; process subscription transactions; provide customer service; notify you about changes to our products or services; send account- or transaction-related communications; send service-related announcements; send you newsletters, RSS feeds, text messages, and/or other communications or services that you have signed up for or otherwise agreed to receive; allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; manage our systems; keep our Site safe and secure; improve online operations; perform research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services and technologies; and display content customized to your interests or preferences. 

We will only use your Personal Information in the ways we specified when it was collected (including as described in this Privacy Statement). 

We may use your non-Personal Information (including but not limited to Personal Information that has been de-identified and/or aggregated) for any reason at StockChart.com's sole discretion. 

## Use of Cookies and Automatic Information Gathering Technologies

### Cookies

StockCharts.com uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies to provide Users with a customized experience on the Site. 

We use a session cookie to control access to our membership areas. Once you close your browser, the session cookie is deleted. 

A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on your hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your browser's help file directions. We use persistent cookies to store your customized user interface preferences. 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser settings to decline cookies. If you reject the use of cookies, you will not be able to access the paid areas of StockCharts.com and you will no longer be able to customize your user interface preferences; however, you will still be able to use the free areas of the Site. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our Site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

### Web Beacons and Other Activity Tracking Technologies

We may use standard Internet activity tracking technologies, such as web beacons and similar technologies, to track your use of our Site, our emails, or our ad content. These beacons do not carry any Personal Information and are only used to monitor general Site usage or track the effectiveness of a particular campaign. 

Though we make every effort to preserve User privacy, we may disclose your Personal Information to third parties when we believe, in good faith and in our sole discretion, that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (1) enforce or apply the terms and conditions of the Site, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (2) comply with legal or regulatory requirements or an enforceable governmental request, (3) protect the rights, property or safety of us, our Users, or other third parties, (4) prevent a crime or protect national security, or (5) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues. 

We may disclose Personal Information and non-Personal Information to employees, companies, agents, contractors, service providers or others engaged to perform functions on our behalf. These companies do not retain, share, store, or use Personal Information for any secondary purpose. 

We may also disclose non-Personal Information (including de-identified, aggregated Personal Information) to our business partners, merchants, investors, potential buyers, and other third parties if we deem such disclosure, at our sole discretion, to have sound business reasons or justifications. 

We do NOT sell, rent, share or trade your Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes. 

Please note also that if you choose to use our social networking function to post information to Facebook, Twitter or another social networking site, anyone who has access to your information through that other site will be able to see your information. Use of social networking functions or other information sharing functions on our Site is considered to be voluntary disclosure of Personal Information by you. 

## Business Transitions

StockCharts.com reserves the right to sell or transfer information (including your Personal and non-Personal Information) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company, or in the unlikely event of a bankruptcy, liquidation, or receivership of our business, and you hereby consent to any such sale or transfer. If any such transfer is required, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you in writing in advance by posting a notice on the Site and/or emailing you at your contact email address of record, and we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the transferee will continue to use any Personal Information collected from you prior to the transfer in accordance with the terms of the then-current version of this Privacy Statement. 

## Updating Personal Information

When you use our Site, we make a good faith effort to provide you with access to your Personal Information and to either correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We provide a way for Users to update their Personal Information on our Site. Paying members can update their information using the ”[Your Account](https://stockcharts.com/youraccount "https://stockcharts.com/youraccount")” link in the upper right corner of any page. For newsletter subscriptions and other types of Site notifications, Users can change their email address simply by unsubscribing the old email address and re-subscribing using the new email address. Users can change their mobile phone number by editing an alert that uses SMS notification on the [Technical Alert Workbench](http://stockcharts.com/h-al/al "http://stockcharts.com/h-al/al"). 

Alternately, Users can send an email to [support@stockcharts.com](mailto:mailto:support@stockcharts.com "mailto:support@stockcharts.com") and request updates or changes to Personal Information. We ask individual Users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected, or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical. 

Please be aware that if you delete your Personal Information, you may not be able to continue to use the Site. Also, even if you request that we delete your Personal Information, we may need to retain certain information for a limited period of time to satisfy our legal, audit, and/or dispute resolution requirements. 

## Opting Out

Users can opt out of providing required Personal Information on the Site by not registering on the Site. However, they may not be able to use all the features of the Site. 

If Users reject the use of cookies, they will not be able to access the members-only areas of the Site. However, they will still be able to use many of the free areas of the Site. 

Members cannot opt out of certain mandatory types of email communications (e.g. service announcements and account administration emails), but they can deactivate their account if they no longer wish to receive such communications. 

All other email communications are optional (e.g. newsletter mailings, blog notifications, or technical alerts). Users can opt out of these communications using the unsubscribe link included at the bottom of the email. They can also opt out by contacting [support@stockcharts.com](mailto:mailto:support@stockcharts.com "mailto:support@stockcharts.com"). 

Users can choose not to use optional features if they do not wish to provide Personal Information required to use those features. 

## Storage and Security

StockCharts.com takes every reasonable precaution to protect our Users' sensitive information - including Personal Information and payment information - from loss, theft, copying, unauthorized disclosure, use, or modification. When Users submit sensitive information via the Site, that information is protected both online and offline. 

StockCharts.com conforms to the [PCI compliance guidelines](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payment_Card_Industry_Data_Security_Standard "https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payment_Card_Industry_Data_Security_Standard") for safe transmission of payment information. We use a third-party service called BrainTree Payments (a division of PayPal) to gather and protect payment information. Payment information (i.e., credit card numbers) are never sent or stored on our servers. Instead, they are transmitted directly to BrainTree. For more on BrainTree's payment protection process, please [click here](https://www.braintreepayments.com/ "https://www.braintreepayments.com/"). 

We also protect our Users' sensitive Personal Information, specifically their user IDs, passwords, and contact information using industry-standard SSL encryption. We also do everything in our power to protect User information offline. All of our Users' information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need to see the information to perform their jobs are allowed access. The servers that store Personal Information are located in a secure environment in a locked facility. Regular backups of private information are kept under lock and key. All employees are briefed regularly on our privacy policy and practices. 

Technical safeguards (including, but not limited to, dedicated firewall computers, passwords, and encryption) are in place to minimize as much as possible the disclosure of sensitive and private User information. We also limit staff access and their ability to enter or view information in the Site based upon their role in your case. 

Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet and no method of data storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its security. You are responsible for keeping the User ID and password you use for accessing our Site and its services confidential. We ask you not to share it with anyone. We strongly recommend that you do not re-use an existing password as the password for your StockCharts.com account. 

When you use our Site on your computing device, your information may be stored locally on that device as well. We cannot guarantee the security of such locally-stored information. 

We reserve the right to retain information collected about you indefinitely for business, legal, or tax purposes. However, we strive to retain this information for only as long as it is necessary for the above purposes, and to destroy it afterwards to prevent unauthorized parties from gaining access to this information. 

## Minors

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from individuals under 13 years of age. Nor do we authorize Users who are less than 13 years old to use the Site. If we learn from the individual or from the individual's parent or legal guardian that we have collected Personal Information about a person under the age of 13, we will delete their Personal Information from our systems within a commercially reasonable period of time. 

## Changes to this Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement is subject to occasional revision. StockCharts.com may modify or update this Privacy Statement periodically with or without prior notice by posting the updated Privacy Statement on the Site. We encourage you to check this Privacy Statement from time to time and to refer to the “Last Updated” date at the top of this document to see when the Privacy Statement was last changed. If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes on this Site and place a notice of such changes on our home page and other places we deem appropriate. 

If we decide to start using Users' Personal Information in a manner different from that stated here at the time of collection, we will notify Users via email and/or by posting a notice on the Site for 30 days. 

Your continued use of our Site following the effective date of an updated Privacy Statement constitutes your consent to the contents of such policy. However, we will not apply any material changes retroactively to any information we collected from you before such changes take effect, without your affirmative consent to do so. 

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO FUTURE CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT, YOU MUST STOP USING OUR SITE AFTER THE EFFECTIVE DATE OF SUCH CHANGES. 

Please note that upon discontinuing use of the Site, any Privacy Statement in effect immediately prior to your departure shall continue to be binding on you and applicable to any data or information (including, without limitation, Personal Information) collected from you prior to such departure. 

## User Consent

By using the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement and expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Information gathered through the Site may be transferred, used, and stored in the United States and in any foreign jurisdictions in which we, our agents, service providers, customers, and other Users of the Site are located. If you use the Site, you consent to the transfer, use, and storage of your Personal Information to and in those jurisdictions. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. You further agree that all transactions relating to the Site shall be deemed to have occurred in the United States. 

This Privacy Statement incorporates by reference StockCharts.com's Terms of Service. By agreeing to the Privacy Statement, you agree to the Terms of Service, and vice versa. 

If you have any questions, comments, requests, complaints, or suggestions regarding our Privacy Statement, or if you believe that we have not complied with our Privacy Statement with respect to your Personal Information or that another User has violated your privacy rights, please contact us using our web-based feedback form or by sending an email to [support@stockcharts.com](mailto:mailto:support@stockcharts.com "mailto:support@stockcharts.com"). We take your privacy very seriously, will carefully consider your inquiries, and will respond as promptly as possible. 

StockCharts.com, Inc.   
11241 Willows Road, Suite 320   
Redmond, WA 98052   
(425) 881-2606
